Cian Tiernan

Software Engineer

+353860303129 •

ciantiernan1997@gmail.com •

http://tierno97.github.io/portfolio25 •

linkedin.com/in/ciantiernan •

About Me

I am a 27 year old Software Engineer based in County Louth looking to find a fresh opportunity in my career. I have 5 years experience working with many technologies but especially with React, Node and Javascript in general. I have used many other languages and frameworks as listed below and feel I would be a strong asset to any team. I also love to be a team player, can adapt quickly and pride myself on thinking outside the box to ensure optimal problem solving. Any references are available on request and find out more in my website linked above!

Professional Experience

Guidewire Software - Dublin, Ireland

Software Engineer II, April 2022 - Present

- Work on various user stories, bugs and tasks in both our software suite and for customers using React and Javascript
- Worked as a part of many teams in an agile system and contributed effectively to meetings and groomings
- Worked on CICD with TeamCity and infrastructure with Docker and Kubernetes
- Worked on writing codemods for customer updates to ensure automation to and from various releases
- · Have worked on many other facets with Javascript, Kotlin, Java/Spring Boot, AWS and Keti
- Wrote efficient united and integration tests and contributed to code reviews

Digigrow Consultants - Dublin, Ireland

Software Engineer, June 2021 - April 2022

- Developed various websites for customers using React, SCSS, NodeJS and MongoDB
- Worked on creating and updating NPM packages
- Developed Rest API's using express and mongoose and used http clients like Postman to test

Inkerman Technologies - Drogheda, Ireland

Software Engineer, June 2020 - June 2021

- Worked on various projects for local business using PHP and React
- Worked on maintaining systems for businesses and implementing updates/features at customers request
- Worked on various projects such as security client manager, booking system, art gallery CMS and finance evaluation system

Key Skills

React • JavaScript • NodeJS • TypeScript • Sass • Postman • Redux • Git • PHP • TeamCity • Kotlin • Java • Docker • MongoDB • Kubernetes • SQL • AWS

Education

Dundalk Institute of Technology - Country Louth, Ireland

Bachelors in Multimedia Web Development, May 2019

Drogheda Institute of Further Education - Country Louth, Ireland

Fetac Level 5 in IT & Computing, May 2015